import { QuestionType, SubjectCode } from "./utils";

const subject_code = SubjectCode.COMMERCE;
export const Commerce: QuestionType[] = [
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "What is the term for the process of buying and selling goods and services?",
    option_a: "Marketing",
    option_b: "Finance",
    option_c: "Commerce",
    option_d: "Economics",
    correct_option: "Commerce",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text: "What is the function of a stock exchange?",
    option_a: "Issuing currency",
    option_b: "Buying and selling stocks",
    option_c: "Managing government finances",
    option_d: "Setting interest rates",
    correct_option: "Buying and selling stocks",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text: "In accounting, what is the balance sheet equation?",
    option_a: "Assets = Liabilities + Equity",
    option_b: "Assets = Expenses + Revenue",
    option_c: "Revenue = Expenses + Equity",
    option_d: "Liabilities = Assets - Equity",
    correct_option: "Assets = Liabilities + Equity",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "What type of financial statement provides a summary of a company's revenues and expenses over a specific period?",
    option_a: "Balance Sheet",
    option_b: "Cash Flow Statement",
    option_c: "Income Statement",
    option_d: "Statement of Retained Earnings",
    correct_option: "Income Statement",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "What is the term for the amount of money charged by a lender for the use of borrowed money?",
    option_a: "Dividend",
    option_b: "Interest",
    option_c: "Royalty",
    option_d: "Equity",
    correct_option: "Interest",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text: "In business, what does the acronym IPO stand for?",
    option_a: "Initial Public Offering",
    option_b: "International Purchase Order",
    option_c: "Inventory and Production Operations",
    option_d: "Internal Policy Oversight",
    correct_option: "Initial Public Offering",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "Which document outlines the terms and conditions of a job, including responsibilities, compensation, and benefits?",
    option_a: "Invoice",
    option_b: "Balance Sheet",
    option_c: "Resume",
    option_d: "Employment Contract",
    correct_option: "Employment Contract",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "What is the economic system where the government owns and controls the means of production?",
    option_a: "Capitalism",
    option_b: "Socialism",
    option_c: "Communism",
    option_d: "Mixed economy",
    correct_option: "Socialism",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "What is the term for a legal entity separate from its owners, providing limited liability?",
    option_a: "Sole Proprietorship",
    option_b: "Partnership",
    option_c: "Corporation",
    option_d: "Cooperative",
    correct_option: "Corporation",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "What is the process of converting raw materials into finished goods for sale called?",
    option_a: "Distribution",
    option_b: "Production",
    option_c: "Procurement",
    option_d: "Promotion",
    correct_option: "Production",
    subject_code,
  },
];
